<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TheWorkAround</title>
    <link>http://theworkaround.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://theworkaround.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>The infinate rambelings and ideas of Brandon Hicks</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 22:01:08 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 22:01:08 -0600</lastBuildDate>

    
    <item>
      <title>Nurture It Like a Garden</title>
      <link>http://theworkaround.com/2013/05/26/nurture-it-like-a-garden.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author> ( {"email"=>"tarellel@gmail.com", "name"=>"Brandon Hicks", "github"=>"tarellel", "twitter"=>"tarellel"} )</author>
      <guid>http://theworkaround.com/2013/05/26/nurture-it-like-a-garden</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/grape_bunch.png&quot; title=&quot;Kumquat Tree&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of recently I have been building and growing a small vegetable garden for my family. My children love the idea of putting
work into it something quite so amazing: digging up the dirt, playing the seeds and plant buds, watering, and taking responsibility for a small living object that will someday be rewarding them for their effort.
But in the meantime they have to put time, effort, and tender love and care into taking care of the plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very much like any project you may work on. It usually starts out as a small idea, like planting a seed in your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It begins by putting a lot of effort into turning that idea into something real, that idea begins to grow into something fruitful and full of life. But in order for your idea to grow into something big and wonderful you need to take care of it, feed it, nourish it, and look after it until it flourishes into something wonderful.
But once it&#39;s alive and growing you can&#39;t just forget about it. You have to look after it, tend to it, make sure it doesn&#39;t get out of control, and is well fed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once an application has reached a satisifing level of use and income you don&#39;t just forget about it and hope it can maintain
itself for the long run. Trends and technology are always advancing, needs, requirements, and desires are always growing.
One day your application my be the top of its category and tomorrow it could be a long forgotten memory of the past (just
look at how fast the social web has jumped around in the past few years). In other words, if you believe in your idea and
dreams don&#39;t let it dwindle and die. Build that idea, make it more than a dream, make it into something that will be used
by someone other than yourself. Success isn&#39;t achieved by just planting the seeds, you have to be patient and maintain
the foundation of what you&#39;ve build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image obtained from - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sxc.hu/photo/1392865&quot;&gt;stock.xchng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Image obtained from - [stock.xchng](http://www.sxc.hu/photo/1402199/) --&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Truth of It All</title>
      <link>http://theworkaround.com/2013/05/20/the-truth-of-it-all.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author> ( {"email"=>"tarellel@gmail.com", "name"=>"Brandon Hicks", "github"=>"tarellel", "twitter"=>"tarellel"} )</author>
      <guid>http://theworkaround.com/2013/05/20/the-truth-of-it-all</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know it&#39;s been asked time and time again, &quot;What do you want in the long run out of your life?&quot; We all have hopes and dreams we want to fulfill, different routes we
want to take through life. But we&#39;re all (well most of us) going to end up the same in the end. We&#39;ll either be stuffed
away like a number in a nursing home or living with out children/grandchildren and feeling bad about them having to help
manage our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality of this question is, its&#39; not as easy of an answer as it seems. And as you live your life and experience new things
your answer will change. When your young and stupid you want fame and money, but as you age and become more mature you
want happiness and health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our outcome in life isn&#39;t always what we&#39;d want it to be. But in the meantime, it&#39;s about making the most you can out of what you love doing.
The reason many people goto college, participate in training seminar, start a hobby, etc. is because they want to spend the bulk of their life doing what they&#39;re passionate about.
You don&#39;t necessarily have to be a millionaire living extravagantly or a philanthropist in order to be happy. But you do want to look back and
tell people you did something amazing with your life, that you weren&#39;t just a couch potato sitting back coasting through life and always hoping for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment my children and fiance, are my number one priorities. But I am still passionate about what makes me happy, with keeps my mind going, and something that pushes my limits.
If you&#39;re deeply passionate about an interest, you don&#39;t just make it a hobby, don&#39;t think about pushing it aside and saying it&#39;s just a phase.
Think about diving head first into it, make a life out of doing what you enjoy. And creating a stable life for you and your family in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Bacon</title>
      <link>http://theworkaround.com/2013/05/19/fresh-bacon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author> ( {"email"=>"tarellel@gmail.com", "name"=>"Brandon Hicks", "github"=>"tarellel", "twitter"=>"tarellel"} )</author>
      <guid>http://theworkaround.com/2013/05/19/fresh-bacon</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yum, a fresh new reset blog is like a fresh new package of bacon.
You don&#39;t know exactly what it&#39;s going to taste like, but you know it&#39;s going to be delicious and full of delight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    

  </channel>
</rss>